Guide to the Brent Nicholson Earle papers,1986-2003.
Earle, Brent Nicholson papers, 1986-2003.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Brent Nicholson Earle papers, 1986-2003.
7457
Brent Nicholson Earle
.3 cubic feet
Manuscripts, printed materials, ephemera.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Informational and publicity materials about the 1986 American Run for the End of AIDS, the 1990 Rainbow Run for the End of Aids, and the 1994 Ranbow Roll, plus Earle's Christmas letters and cards sent to friends and supporters; occasional announcements and letters regarding ongoing activities of A.R.E.A; obituaries and a eulogy for Marion Nicholson; a copy of an article by Earle in New York Newsday about Magic Johnson; 2 A.R.E.A. t-shirts; a broadside; and other material related to his AIDS activism.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
In 1985, Earle planned The American Run for the End of AIDS (A.R.E.A.), a 10,000 mile run around the perimeter of the United States, which he ran from March 1986 to October 1987. On June 7, 1990 he set off from San Francisco and arrived in Vancouver, Canada on August 4 for the beginning of the third Gay Games held there that year. He was assisted in his AIDS activism by his mother, Marion Nicholson, until her death in 1991. On April 29, 1994, he left San Francisco, this time leading a 7-person team on the Rainbow Roll, a trek on rollerblades, carrying a rainbow flag through 22 cities and ending up in New York City on June 16 for the start of the fourth Gay Games. On each trek, Earle worked to raise awareness and knowledge about AIDS and to raise money for AIDS service organizations. In 1990, People Magazine named Earle one of its "20 individuals who shaped the 80's." He has continued work as an AIDS activist.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Informational and publicity materials about the 1986 American Run for the End of AIDS, the 1990 Rainbow Run for the End of Aids, and the 1994 Ranbow Roll, plus Earle's Christmas letters and cards sent to friends and supporters; occasional announcements and letters regarding ongoing activities of A.R.E.A; obituaries and a eulogy for Marion Nicholson; a copy of an article by Earle in New York Newsday about Magic Johnson; 2 A.R.E.A. t-shirts; a broadside; and other material related to his AIDS activism.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Earle, Brent Nicholson.; Nicholson, Marion.
Subjects:
AIDS (Disease); AIDS (Disease)--Political aspects.; Gay athletes.; Sports--Political aspects.; Gay men--Family relationships.; Parent and child.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Collecting Program: Human Sexuality Collection.
CONTAINER LIST
- Poster: A.R.E.A., The American Run for the End of AIDS (Folder 1)
- T-shirt: A.R.E.A., The American Run for the End of AIDS, Mar. 1, 1986-Oct. 31, 1987 (Box 1)
- T-shirt: Rainbow Run for the End of AIDS, Jun. 7-Aug. 4, 1990 (Box 1)
- T-shirt: A.R.E.A., The American Run for the End of AIDS, 10th Anniversary (Box 1)
- Gay Games II Program and Brochure about A.R.E.A., 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Press Packet, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Brent Nicholson Earle, article in New York Newsday, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Marion M. Nicholson memorials, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Advocate article, World AIDS Day flyer, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Annotated "Circus for Life" Program, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Rainbow Roll, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- A.R.E.A. Mailing: Tenth Anniversary of A.R.E.A., 1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- A.R.E.A. Mailing, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- A.R.E.A. Mailing, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Brent Nicholson Earle, family and friends letter, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 11)